MANISHA

MEAN / MERN / Full Stack / AWS Cloud-Serverless / Devops

A Full-Stack consultant with extensive proven experiences related to software development, currently working as a Team Lead. For the last few years, my forte has been Javascript. I follow agile methodologies and best practices to bring the ideas into life from scratch and to scale it up on Cloud. I am a Docker, CI/CD, and Serverless enthusiast. I always believe in perfecting my craft and so making strides to learn everything that I can about development.

PERSONAL INFO

7992480960

https://manishamuskan.github.io/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/manishamuskan/

EXPERIENCES IN BRIEF

Practice **Agile** Development Methodology

Analyze Project / Business Requirements

Design Solution with Best Practices in Mind

Work with Serverless Architecture (AWS)

Project Deployment with CI/CD Integration(AWS)

Build and Manage Team

Take Ownership of End-to-End Project

Help with UI/UX and Restful APIs

Achieve 80%-90% Test Coverage

Create Reusable Modules

On-Time Delivery of Projects

Demo / Presentation to Clients

NEW INTERESTS

Blockchain

Cofounded - NESTAGEN PVT LTD

EDUCATION

Masters in Computer Application IGNOU, Ranchi 2017

Bachelors in Computer Application Ranchi University (St. Xavier's College) 2013

HANDS ON EXPERIENCES

UI/UX Designing Html 5 | CSS3 / SCSS | Bootstrap / Materialize CSS |

Media query

Development Angular 6+ | Angular JS | React JS (+ redux) | Ionic |

Node JS | ES 6/7 | TS

Code Coverage Mocha | Karma | Jest | Jasmine | Assertion Libraries

Databases NO-SQL/SQL

Deployment / Devops /

Others

AWS Serverless (IAM, Lamda, S3, Route53, DynamoDb, EC2, EBS, Cognito) | Cloud Native | Docker | Kubernetes | Jenkins | Git Actions | Travis CI | JIRA | Git Flow | Nginx

Apache

CAREER SUMMARY

Magnitude Software Pvt Ltd, Bangalore

June 2020 - *

Serving as **Sr. Software Engineer**, positioned as a Team lead. Revamping the product from a Traditional solution developed in .Net to Javascript Frameworks one feature at a time and managing a small team of 5.

CodeCraft Technologies Pvt Ltd, Bangalore

Mar 2020 - May 2020

Served as Lead Software Engineer leading a team of 8. Designing Code reviews, Architectural Decisions, **Client Interactions, New Hiring and Training**

Delivery Centric Pvt Ltd, Bangalore

Oct 2018 - Jan 2020

Served as Sr. MEAN stack Developer, later on promoted to Team lead. Designed the product solution and managed the development teams.

Whyable Technologies Pvt Ltd, Bangalore

Apr 2018 - Sep 2018

Served as Sr. Software Developer, responsible for endto-end delivery of the projects. Was also introduced to microservices architecture during project development.

Ubique IT Solutions Pvt Ltd, Ranchi

Oct 2016 - Mar 2018

Served as Lead Web Developer, mentored junior UI/UX developers in the team and trained interns. Most of the work was related to developing Client Web Apps. Used MVC framework / .Net as the main tech framework coupled with Vanilla HTML/CSS

PROJECTS SUMMARY

EVERY ANGLE (Web Application)

Magnitude Software Pvt Ltd, Bangalore

Mar 2020 - May 2020

Project Requirement

EveryAngle is an analytical product company which was acquired by Magnitude. In a nutshell EveryAngle basically provides business insights for SAP by extracting data stored in HANA. It helps in analyzing data and creating key business reports for business that would empower them by providing deep understanding of the business issues within the organization and help in developing/driving strategies to boost their performance and gain business expertise. This project is being revamped according to latest trends and new features are being introduced with a lot of things which would automate a lot of tedious tasks within the system.

NURTURE ME (Node+React Application)

CodeCraft Tech. Pvt Ltd, Bangalore

Mar 2020 - May 2020

Project Requirement

The project requirement was to make a **HIPPA compliant** application for Montefiore Org. The Application served as an Interface between Patient and the Health Specialists/Consultants mainly for Cancer Patients. Dietitians Doctors Patients each had a role based application's view that helped them to interact and guide them and ease their journey with the Organization.

CRYPTO - AUTO TRADER (Node Application)

Delivery Centric Pvt Ltd, Bangalore

Jul 2019 - Jan 2020

Project Requirement

The project requirement was to make a console application to automate the trading (buy / sell) of Cryptocurrencies based on market insights and certain strategies. This is an inhouse Project to make profits using current stock assets as well as to keep a maintained in/outflow, stock of crypto supply for the CryptoCentric Project

Approaches and Achievements

Worked and successfully lead a the project
Automated login to the different third Parties such as Binance, Bittrex
Intelligent Pricing module to optimize profits based on strategies.
Creating webhooks based on custom Email client and Triggering a trade based on it

CRYPTOCENTRIC (Last Project - Web Application)

Delivery Centric Pvt Ltd, Bangalore

Oct 2018 - Jul 2019

Project Requirement

The requirement was to build a secure *Crypto Currency Exchange* similar to an e-commerce platform that deals with the buy and sells of crypto currencies such as Bitcoin, Ether, and other digital coins for the Australian Market. A similar project CoinCentric already existed but was not as reliable, secure & modular as per the current needs, and was developed using MULESOFT, OIM, OAM, Oracle DB and .Net and few other traditional technologies.

Approach Followed

Breaking down the requirements into independent modules keeping **Micro-services** in mind.

Architecting a **cloud based solution** from scratch using **MEAN** as tech stack.

Used **JIRA** to keep track of project modules progress & **Docker** for containerization.

Used **JWT Token** to implement **role and session based authorization / authentication**.

Integrated third party services such as **POLI payments, SMS, Google Services** etc.

Development of modules like **OTP module, KYC Verification module, Payment and Transaction module** etc.

Deployment on AWS EBS and Use of Bit-bucket and Jenkins to achieve CI/CD.

Setting up load balancer to handle more requests.

Achievements

30% Faster Turn Around in Development
A much more enhanced Security
Monolithic to Micro-services with scale on demand in mind, running on cloud
Cut the Product cost by 40% using Open Source Technologies.

ODE SYSTEMS (Hybrid Application)

Brief Project Description

Whyable Technologies Pvt Ltd, Bangalore

Jul mid 2018 - Sep 2019

ODE Systems was regarding the development of **chart based hybrid application** that helps the user to make a decision out of two or more choices based on the criterion created by the user himself. Followed **MEAN Stack** approach along with **lonic** Framework. Created **API solutions** and **Reusable components** in angular. Used **PouchDB** to **sync the application state** online as well as offline. I also created **plug and play UI utility example code page (UI Sink)** for internal team by using HTML/SCSS only so that the UI utilities can be reused anywhere regardless of framework or library. Deployed on **App Store & Play Store**.

INVISIBLE CITY (Hybrid Application)

Brief Project Description

Whyable Technologies Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore

Apr 2018 - Jun 2018

The project was about making an emotions based solution where users can register and can give feedback about the place they have visited, very similar to Google places app but for the Australian population only. The whole purpose of the project was to keep track of people's emotions tagged to a particular place that is supposed to be used by the research and development team of the client's University for the Australian population. Technologies used to develop this project are **lonic**, **NodeJs**, **Express Js and MongoDB and D3 JS charting library** to create an overlapping chart. **Location Clustering** was used to avoid location collision. We used **S3 buckets** to store the image files uploaded by the user. I integrated **Social login** feature for the project and created admin panel. As tools, I used **Android Studio** and **Xcode** to build the application for android and IOS mobile platform respectively. I also deployed the applications in their respective marketplaces. I deployed the project in **AWS (EC2 instance)** also implemented **CI/CD** for this project.

FILE IDS (Web Applications)

Brief Project Descriptions

Ubique IT Solutions Pvt Ltd, Ranchi

Dec 2016 - Mar 2018

This project was developed in many phases. In that development cycle, the requirement was to make the process of filing IDS hassle-free. The application requires some patent-related details and auto-fill the rest of the form by consuming EPO's data (**OPS web services**). I used .**Net(C#)** with **Jquery** to develop the complete solution, Integrated **OAuth 2.0 Authentication** with **AJAX** requests to consume the APIs.

Few other projects include creating Admin panels with different roles and functionalities. I used the design prototype provided by UX designer and created the **Pixel Perfect Responsive UI** for both customers as well as the admin end from scratch.

Considered **Mobile-First-Approach** during entire UI development process. I was introduced to **Restful APIs** as backend and **angular JS framework** for front-end development.